People say that when someone dies, they go to Heaven.
人が死んだら 天国に行けるという
でも 僕はそうは思わない
But I don't think that's the case.
When someone dies, I think that person journeys into people's hearts.
死んだ人間は きっと誰かの心へ旅立つのだ
思い出となって 生き続けるのだ
They live on as a memory.
父と母がそうだったように
Just like how my mother and father currently live on in our hearts.
僕らの心に宿るのだ
けれど それもやがて消えていく
But memories eventually fade with time.
That's why people want to leave something behind...
だから 人は何かを残したいと願うのだ
So others won't forget them.
忘れてしまわないように
ちゃんと映ってんのかな
Is it recording?
The viewfinder is black...
ファインダー真っ黒だけど
忘れないように
So we'll remember them.
なっ 何だ
What's that?!
あ きれいな手
Her hands were so beautiful.
手
Huh?
あれ俺 どうして
What? Why am I...
Let's see, what did I do yesterday...
それで 海君
えっと 昨日は 高感度フィルムのテストをしようと思って
I went out to test my new high-speed camera,
そろそろ起きないと遅刻しちゃうわよ
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，请登录www：Kamigami：org
日听：秋水无痕 翻译：yaya 校对：小草爱吃梨 gin 时间轴：小青
and then...
Kai! It's time for you to wake up! You'll be late for school!
Okay...
海外出張
You're going abroad?
Just for three months, you know.
まあ 三ヶ月だけなんだけどね
ああ どこに
Where are you going?
Bolivia. My company needs people there.
ボリビア 人手が足りないんだって
Hey, Kai...
ねえ 海君
Will you be fine without me?
お姉ちゃん 行ってきていいかな
You're looking forward to it, aren't you?
行きたいんでしょう
Just go.
いいよ 行っておいでよ
I can take care of myself, and summer break is just around the corner anyway.
俺 自炊できるし
もうすぐ 夏休みだし
Don't throw wild parties in my absence.
一人になるからって羽目外しすぎちゃダメよ
Of course not.
はい はい
Also, mind your manners.
それと お行儀悪い
I'll do some shopping on the way home, but I'll be back before seven at the latest.
帰りに買い物とかしてくるけど
七時までには 帰るから
Got it.
分かった 行ってらっしゃい
Take care.
You too.
そっちも行ってらっしゃい
Home alone, huh?
一人暮らしか
This'd make a pretty picture.
うん いいロケーション
Red hair...
赤い 髪
Why... Why?
なぜ どうして
Why is everyone staring at me?
こんなに目立ってるの
What did I do wrong?
何か 間違ってるのかしら
So, Kai, where will you shoot it?
でさ ロケ場所は決まったの 海君
Huh?
Weren't you scouting for a location yesterday?
昨日 ロケハンに行ってたんじゃないの
You had your camera with you.
それ持って
No, I was just trying it out yesterday.
いや 昨日はただフィルムのテストし
Got a movie idea in mind, Mr. Director?
映画撮るんだろう 監督
I'm just recording things I see. Nothing else.
適当に取ってるだけだよ
ただ なんとなく
Come on... I was gonna help you too.
何だよ
手伝ってやろうと思ったのに
But if Tetsuro stars in it, all the girls would get wet.
けどけど 哲郎君が映画に出たら
女子たちぎゃあぎゃあ言いそうかも
Oh really?
そう
I don't see the problem.
俺はいいよ
But what about you, Mio?
つうかさ 美桜こそどうよ
海 美桜主演で行かねえ
Kai, how about filming Mio?
It's summer, so we could shoot something like an idol promo video...
夏だし アイドルのイメージビデオっぽくさ
どうよ
What do you think?
No cost involved, and you don't need a script.
金もかからず 脚本も要らない
Now that I think about it...
なるほど
They're thinking about... imagining me...
ぎょ凝視されてる 想像されてる うわ
Men sure are carnal creatures.
男子の欲望出まくり
Just kidding. But you know...
冗談だって
けどさ
I'd love to do something.
何かしたいね
Something? Such as?
何かって 何
Dunno...
分かんないけど
何かさ
Just something.
Yeah, we're high schoolers after all.
まあそうだな 何せ 俺ら 高校生だし
And it's summer.
夏だし
You're right.
そうだね 何かしなくちゃかも
We should do something during the holidays.
Well, well...
へえ 何撮ってんのかと思えば
I was wondering what you filmed with so much devotion...
So she's your type.
ああいうのがタイプなんだ
まだ カメラ回ってるよ
The camera's still recording.
You've got it wrong...
いや だから そう言うんじゃなくて
I see.
なるほど 確かに さっきの人 柑菜とは正反対のタイプだな
She's pretty much the complete opposite of Kanna.
ちょ どういう意味
Hey! How exactly?
In many ways.
いろいろと
I asked you how exactly!
だから どういう意味
And I said, "In many ways."
だから いろいろだよ
How could you be less specific? You're always...
何よ それ
大体あんた まあまあ 落ち着きなよ 柑菜
Come on, just calm down.
The truth was right before my eyes.
当然ながら 僕は気づいてなかった
Staff room
I apologize for being late.
遅れてすみません
I'm supposed to attend school here from now on.
今日から こちらの学校に転入させていただきます
My name is Takatsuki Ichika.
貴月 イチカです
The drama we're all a part of
僕たちのドラマは
The bell's already rung! Homeroom, everyone!
ほら ホームルームはじめるよ
has already started.
すでに動き出していること
Open your books.
It's already being caught on film.
カメラが回り始めていること
Takatsuki Ichika
Tell me about the clubs you used to be in!
前の学校で部活とかしてた
Getting a transfer student halfway through is kind of unusual.
こんな時期 転校とか 珍しいよね
I love the color of your hair.
髪の色 きれいだね
Do you have a boyfriend?
付き合ってるやつとか
Come on. Buzz off, you hungry beasts.
ほらほら 散りなさい
飢えた狼ども
What's wrong, Yamano?
何何だよ 山乃
Get off our case.
いいだろ 別に
She's our classmate now!
クラスメートだし
Get yourselves in line,
あんたたち おとなしくしないと
or I'm gonna have some fun.
すごいことするわよ
You free this afternoon?
今日の昼何する
So, like, yesterday on TV...
そうそう 昨日のテレビさ
I'm Yamano Lemon.
私 山乃檸檬
あっ えっと
I'm Takatsuki Ichika.
貴月 イチカです
Is something weird about me?
あれ 何かおかしいですか
I think this is the beginning of a beautiful friendship.
私たち いい友達になれそうね
Do you?
そ そう
Um, Yamano...
山乃さん
Just call me Lemon.
檸檬でいいわ
Okay, Lemon. Can I ask you something?
うん じゃあ 檸檬 一つ聞いていい
Go on.
何かしら
Why are you wearing a different uniform?
なぜ 違う制服を着てるの
Can't tell. Top secret.
内緒 すげえ内緒
そっ そう
I see...
Anyway, that's a weird combination.
それにしても 何か 偏った組み合わせね
えっ 何かおかしいかしら
What's wrong with it?
I have carbohydrates, a drink...
炭水化物と水分 平均的な組み合わせじゃない
Isn't that what you normally buy?
Is there maybe some regional specialty—
何か珍奇的な食べ物とか
You're a weird one.
あなた 変わってるわ
How? In what way?
ど どこが どんな風に
That's it, exactly.
そういうところが
名前は貴月イチカさん
Her name is Takatsuki Ichika.
She's in Class 3-A as of today.
今日つけて 三年A組に転入
She's 160 cm tall. Weight is 41 kg.
身長は１６０センチ 体重四十一キロ
Her measurements are 92-56-88.
３サイズは上から ９２ ５８ ８８
Her shoe size is...
靴のサイズは
Where are you getting this from?
どうやって調べた
Where, you ask?
どうって
Professor,
先生 三年に転入してきた 先輩のプロフィル
can you tell me some things  about the third-year girl who transferred here today?
教えてもらえませんか
Well... fine, Ishigaki.
もう
石垣君ったら ほかの人に言っちゃダメよ
But don't spread it around.
That's how the story goes.
とまあ そんな感じで
Isn't that somehow against the law?
犯罪じゃないか それ
「ありがとう」は
Where's the gratitude?
ありがとう
Thank you!
You're welcome.
どういたしまして
こんなところで何してんの
What are you doing here?
Oh, Tanigawa.
谷川 や もうめし食ったのか
Hey. Ate lunch already?
Yeah.
うん ああ そういうこと
Oh, I get it now.
また隠し撮りでもするつもり
Are you going to stalk someone with your camera again?
Absolutely not!
違うよ あれはたまたま シャッターを押しただけで
I must've hit record by accident.
Lies!
ウソ ホントだって
Seriously!
What?
何
ああ もう 叩きたい 痛いんでんじゃん
I wanna beat the crap outta you!
You already are!
Shut up!
Lover's quarrel.
うるさい
痴話喧嘩だ
Tanigawa, stop it!
Okay, let's do it!
よし 決めた
I can't do it! I don't have any cute bikinis or stuff like that!
私 無理だから 可愛い水着とか持ってないしだから
Hey, let's go!
海 行くぞ
Huh?
行くってどこに
Go? Where?
Hey, is something wrong with my food...
ねっ ねえ 私のご飯 どこが
Hello!
こんにちは
すいません ちょっといいですか
Sorry, can I have a moment?
Come on, Tetsuro...
おい 哲郎 お前 何する気だよ
What are you doing?
I got this.
いいから 任せとけって
Uh, okay.
いや 別に
So, what is it?
えっと 何
You're Takatsuki Ichika, right? The one who transferred today.
あのう 今日転入してきた貴月イチカ先輩ですよね
I'm first-year Ishigaki Tetsuro.
俺は 一年の石垣哲郎
This is Kirishima Kaito.
こっちは霧島海人です
We were thinking of making a movie with our friends in it,
実は 俺たち 仲間中で自主映画撮ろうとしてて
and I thought it'd be nice to have you in it too!
で 先輩 よかったら 俺らの映画に出演してもらえませんか
What?!
What?
What's that all about now?
おい 急に何言い出すんだ
I'll do it.
いいわよ
I mean, if you really want me in it,
その 私でよかったら
I'd be happy to help.
ぜひ 協力させて
Once something starts moving,
一度動き出したものは簡単には止まらない
it's hard to bring it to rest again.
Very well.
ちなみに 私も参加するわ
I'll be in it too.
What?
はい？
I'm third-year Yamano Lemon. Nice to meet you.
三年の山乃檸檬
Before I knew it,
よろしく 自分でも気づかないうちに
Third-year?!
えっ 三年 年上
You're older than us?
the camera had already begun to roll.
カメラは 回り始めていたんだ
Episode One
You shouldn't do that.
You just have to ask others.
いや 言ってみるもんだな
You can all relax
at the pool this period.
まさか オーケーしてくれるのは思わなかったよ
Of course, even I was surprised that she accepted.
Ichika is so forthcoming.
イチカ先輩 気前よすぎ
You're mental.
むちゃくちゃだよ お前
思いだったら すぐ実行
Act on your impulses!
That's my motto!
俺のポリシーね
I'm feeling awesome.
いや 気分がいいな
The view is great here too.
眺めも最高
You sound like an old lecher.
オヤジ癖
Hey, are you really making a movie?
ねえねえ ホントに作るの
映画
We've already told the third-years.
先輩に宣言しちゃったしな
Right?
What's it gonna be about?
ど どんな内容にするのかな
We're just going to leave that to our tiny senior Lemon.
そこらへんはちっちゃい檸檬先輩に任せればいいさ
なんせ
She said...
ああ 映画の内容は私に任せて
Yeah, just leave the script to me.
I have a book with scripts I wrote for Lucas.
ちょうど ルーカスのために書いておいた本があるから
Hollywood level?!
ハリウッド級
You were just doodling, right?
ってか 勝手に書いただけですよね
Tehehe.
That's what she said.
とか言ってたし
All right.
分かった
Count me in too, then.
じゃ 私も参加する
私も 裏方とかなら 手伝えるかも
Me too. Maybe I can help out backstage.
いやいや 美桜は出演しろよ
No, you belong on film, Mio!
No way! No way!
そんな ダメダメ
Why? You'd be great!
何で いいじゃん ダメだよ
A movie, huh?
映画 ね
監督 演技指導 お願いして いい
Director...
Can you teach me how to act?
Then I'll start with the ins and unders...
じゃ 手取り 腰取り
You mean ins and outs.
足取りですよ
いや はあああ
What's so funny?
何笑ってんの
Nothing.
いや なんでも
By the way, what's that?
ていうか 何それ
これよこれ
This, here!
What?
えっ 何が
Isn't that a hickey?
それ キスマークじゃねえ
What?
はい
Here.
Are you prepared for anything?
よ 用意いい ってなんだこれ
Huh, what's this?!
I'm telling you, it's a hickey.
だから キスマーク
It's not!
違うよ 昨日撮影してたときにでも虫に刺されたんだよ
I guess some bug bit me while I was filming yesterday!
ったく そんなの身に覚えがないって
Damn, I don't remember anything, tho—
He... suddenly fell silent...
な なんか 沈黙してる
Has it come to you?
見 見に覚えが
So, what was it you "discovered"?
おいおい どんなロケしてんだよ
That's not what happened!
違うって
The peasants demanded that their tax be lowered.
農民による地租軽減
The bourgeoisie demanded the freedom to associate with other classes.
庶民なによる自由な言論集会の改正
よかった
I'm glad.
Many demanded that the country open itself to the world.
他国との対等条約の締結要請
He seems to be all right.
元気そうで
These three currents...
え これら三つの主張を掲げ
Tomorrow when summer break starts, let's all meet up and talk about the movie.
じゃ 明日の休みは皆で集まって
映画製作の決起集会ね
Okay...
檸檬先輩たちには 俺から連絡しとくわ
I'll call the third-year girls myself.
See you all tomorrow, then.
じゃ お先
おう
Sure.
See you tomorrow!
また明日
Yeah.
じゃあ 私も
I'm going home too.
お 気をつけてな
Sure, take care.
He's really looking forward to it.
あれで意外と楽しみにしてんだぜ 海人
Kaito, I mean.
Are you sure?
そうなの
Yeah.
そう
余計なことしたか
Do you think this was a mistake?
What was?
何が
ま きっかけは多いほうがいいだろ
The more chances there are, the better.
頑張んな
Hang in there.
そういう上から目線 なんかむかつくんですけど
It kinda pisses me off when you look down on people like that!
Why am I so happy?
何浮かれてんだ 俺
でも 映画か
This movie thing is a bit unexpected...
あれって
Huh, is that...
I'm doing it right. I must be.
これで 間違ってないはずだけど
What are you doing?
何してんっすか
Oh, uh...
ええっと
海人です 霧島海人
My name's Kaito. Kirishima Kaito.
ああ 海人君
Oh, Kaito.
Why are you here?
でも どうして
I saw you from over there.
いや あそこから見えたんで
You're fishing, right?
で それ釣りですよね
そ そうなの 私 こういうのが趣味なの
Yeah! I've always liked fishing.
That's nice to know, but...
それはそれでいいんですけど
この川 魚いませんよ
There are no fish in this river.
あっ ありがとう 教えてくれて
Th-Thanks for telling me.
I'm glad I could help you.
お役に立てて何よりです
私 まだ この辺 よく分からなくて
I'm new here. I don't know a lot of things.
とっても助かっちゃった
That was really nice of you.
あの 釣りなら もう少し行くと 大きな川にぶつかるんで
I-If you want to fish, there's a bigger river with fish not that far away.
そこなら きっと
じゃあ 俺はこれで
Well then, if you'll excu...
It's okay.
ううん 何でも その これからよろしく
I guess I'll be seeing you around.
あっ はい こちらこそ よろしく
Oh yeah.
See you around, then.
え 惜しいことしたかな
Did I waste my chance?
こうもうちょっと会話を繋げてさ
I should've stuck with her for a bit longer.
Maybe, just maybe...
何と言うか こう
ずばり言いましょう
Let's be honest.
イチカ先輩は一人でここへ引っ越してきたんですね
I believe you moved here alone, Ichika?
Wow! How did you know?
すっごい どうして分かったの
その手にしている荷物を見れば分かります
It's obvious from the luggage you're carrying.
簡単なプロファイリングですよ
I'm something of an armchair detective.
I concluded you must be alone and looking for a place to stay.
そして 俺は更にこう推理しました
先輩は住む場所がなくて困っている
Completely right again!
またまたすごい
下宿先と何かトラブルがあった
You can't stay where you thought you could.
ピンポン ピンポン
Ding, ding, ding!
And so you're at a loss.
正直路頭に迷ってる
あんな場所で釣りをしていたのが何よりの証拠です
The fact that you were trying to fish there proves that.
Ding, ding, once again!
またまたピンポン
あのう 俺んち来ませんか
Well then...
Wanna stay at my place?
Well, if you don't mind.
イチカ先輩さえよければ だけど
Are you sure I could?
本当にいいの
もちろんです ちなみに ここが僕の家です
Of course.
By the way, this is my house.
ああ 大きなお家
It's so huge!
死んだばあちゃんの家なんです
It was my dead grandma's.
It's so huge half of it can't be taken care of.
大きすぎで 持て余すほどです
You couldn't possibly make it worse.
先輩一人増えても どうってことはありません
Sounds wonderful!
素敵
Also, if we live together, I could teach you this and that about how to act in movies.
それに 一緒にいれば 映画の演技指導もできますから
All the ins and unders!
それこそ 手取り 腰取り
I think you mean ins and outs.
それは足取りだと思うけど
は そうでした
Oh really?
Wait, dream's over?
で これ 現実ですか
あはい
Huh?
How long have you been standing there?
えと いつから
結構前から
For a while now.
海人君
Kaito?
But I'm really glad, you know.
でも すごく助かる
私 本当に困ってたから
I didn't know what to do.
あの 何の話す
What are you talking about?
えっ 来ませんか 俺んちって
The "Wanna stay at my place?" part.
そこから聞いてた
So that's where you tuned in, huh?
で ちょっと待ってください
Wait a second.
That was just me talking to myself.
先のは その 俺の妄想っていうか
独り言で
Besides, my sister lives here too.
それに うちには姉さんがいるんです
いきなり 女の子を家に連れ込んだりしたら
I don't know what she would say if I suddenly brought a girl home with me...
そっとうしちゃうと思うし
そうだね
You're right...
Yeah, that's true...
だよね
I get it.
分かってる
Sorry I came here.
ごめんなさい 無理を言って
あの 先輩 どこへ
Where are you going?
この辺で
I'll try to pitch a tent somewhere.
どこか 野宿のしやすそうな場所に
ああ もう
Ah, fuck!
Hi, Nanami!
あれ 七海さん
あら 柑菜ちゃん
Hey, Kanna!
珍しいですね こんな早くにこんな場所で
It's rare to see you around here so early.
仕事は引き継ぎだけだったし 用意もあったから
I'm just doing someone else's job, and I had to get ready...
用意
Ready?
そう なのに こいつが急に機嫌悪くなっちゃって
Yeah. But my bike decided to break down on me.
Oh right. Kanna, can you lend me a hand here?
そうだ 柑菜ちゃん
よかったら ちょっとお手伝ってくれないかな
What?
はい
その辺座っててください
Make yourself at home.
I'll put your luggage...
ああ 荷物は取りあえず こっちに
おもっ
This is so heavy!
どうやってここまで
How did you get it here?
Gravi—
ああ グラビ
Gravi?
グラ
Oh, I gradually got used to it. There's a trick to it.
ぐらっとさせてね コツがあるの
とりあえず 一晩だけですよ
This is just for one night, you know.
You can stay here tonight, and then...
今晩だけは 泊めますから
なんです
What's so interesting?
ごめんなさい 男の子の部屋に入るの 初めてだから
Sorry, this is my first time in a boy's room.
Oh really?
そっ そうなんですか
そうだ こんなにのんびりしてられないんです
Right! We shouldn't just bum around.
食事は後で持ってきますから じゃなくて
I'll bring you some food later— Well, actually, no...
My sister will come home around seven, so you should take a shower before then.
その前に姉さんが帰ってくるのが七時ぐらいだから
今のうちに シャワーを
Do you have your clothes in there?
着替え この中ですか
Sorry...
ご ごめんなさい
What's in it?
何入れてるんですか あれ
Okay, so this is the shampoo...
えっと こっちがシャンプーで
Pajamas, pajamas...
パジャマ パジャマ
So Nanami likes negligees...
ねえちゃん ネグリジェ派だった
This should do fine.
とりあえず 着るものは
着 着替え 洗濯機の上に置いときますから
I put some clothes for you on the washing machine.
ありがとう
Thanks!
Keep it closed!
開けなくていいです
まだ七時までには 結構あるな
There's still some time until seven.
ったく 何って日だ
Man, today is killing me.
先輩と会って
I met her...
映画作ることになって
I'm making a movie with her...
なぜか先輩が家にいて
And now she's sleeping at my place for some reason.
Well, I have to clean up my stuff for now and get changed.
とにかく 俺も荷物を片付けて 着替えして
This needs fixing too.
そうか これも 片付けとかなくちゃ
何だ ここって 虫に刺された
Ouch!
Is this where the bug bit me?
な 何だ これ
What's going on...
Kaito, these clothes are...
海人君 この服なんだけど
海人君
Kaito?!
海人君 海人君
Kaito! Kaito!
What's wrong?
どうしたの しっかり
Wake up!
海人君
Kaito!
The metabolism... of his cells...
これは セルの代謝が
Rinon!
りのん
I'm glad it works...
よかった 機能してる
ごめん ごめんね
Sorry... I'm sorry.
大丈夫だから ね
You'll be fine.
You were a big help!
ホント助かったわ
ありがとうね 柑菜ちゃん
Thanks, Kanna.
いえいえ でも 三ヶ月の転勤ですか
No sweat. But will you really be gone for three months?
Yep. Take care of Kai for me.
そうなの 柑菜ちゃん 海君のこと頼むわね
なんなら 泊まりに来ちゃってもいいから
Just stay here if you want.
そ そんな
Yeah right!
お姉ちゃん 柑菜ちゃんのこと 応援してるんだけどな
I'm rooting for you, Kanna!
What do you mean?!
ど どういう意味ですか
あら とぼけちゃって
Oh, please.
I, uh...
どうしたんですか
What's wrong?
You know, I should see an optometrist.
おねえちゃん また 目が悪くなったみたいで
なんかね 光に包まれながら 海君が女の人と抱き合ってる幻が
I saw this illusion of Kai being held by some girl while they were surrounded by light.
何ですか それ おかしい
Oh, come on. You can't be serious.
I know, right?
ホントよね
Uh...
ああ あの
This isn't...
これは
Wha—
な なななななな 何してんのおおおっ ハメを外しすぎっっ
What?!
That's really embarrassing!
What are you doing?!
Um...
あの とりあえず 離れて
Just get away from him!
As you may well realize, I was unconscious.
当然ながら 僕は気づいていなかった
Dynamite!
All I know is...
知っているのは
残っているのは
All that's left is...
With her...
Episode Two
I don't want you...
These overflowing feelings...
...to find out.
...won't stop.
あなたには 溢れ出す思いが
知られたくないから
止まらなくて